sebastian belmar

software engineer

🗷 si.belmar@gmail.com 🚱 sebabelmar.github.io 📞 415 314 9542 in sebastianbelmar 🖸 sebabelmar

I have 8 years of experience as an engineer specializing in finance and software development. I have worked in a wide range of industries like finance, sustainability and climate change, educational technology, education and consumer goods. For the last 4 years, I have been focused on developing software as a full-stack engineer. I have demonstrable good eye for design too.

notable achievements

- Member of top performing engineering team at largest EdTech company in the world
- Successful EdTech startup exit in less than a year as 2nd engineer in 9 person company -UClass
- E-commerce startup cofounder featured in INC Magazine
- Creative director and designer for 2 successful Kickstarter campaigns. Raised +75k
- · Creator of FinTech calculator used with biggest airline in Latin America

employment

Actua Sedona, AZ Lead Software Engineer

Jan 2017 to Current

Gathered requirements, designed and implemented actuarial calculator application built with Ruby on Rails, MongoDB and Postgres

- Designed architecture to be used as an internal tool at a financial services company
- Optimized databases to process benefit information for +8,500 employees and calculate the present value of the earned portion of individual benefits to date
- Implemented configurability to perform sensitivity tests on different variables, aggregating results to report on regulated financial statements

Mason Bottle Sedona, AZ Software Engineer | Cofounder

Dec 2016 to Current

- Developed and maintained e-commerce store using Shopify Liquid (Ruby templating) and Javascript
- Positioned store in top 3% of all stores launched the same week
- Responsible for digital marketing strategy and business development

Dev Bootcamp
Software Engineer | Instructor

Mar 2016 to Dec 2016

- Developed features for educational software using Ruby on Rails
- Taught Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, MEAN stack and libraries like React, React Native, AngularJS, jQuery, Sinatra
- Advised on architecture and team dynamics for +20 web applications

Renaissance Learning

San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer Feb 2015 to Feb 2016

- Developed several API's for service oriented architecture using C#, .Net and MongoDB, used by 1.5 million users a
- Developed single-page applications for data visualization using .Net, AngularJS and D3
- Developed multiple customizable AngularJS directives for front-end infrastructure

UClass San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer

Sep 2014 to Feb 2015

Acquired by Renaissance Learning in February 2015.

- Developed data visualization platform used by 7,000 users
- Restructured front-end architecture using AngularJS directives
- Developed several features using Ruby on Rails back-end, AngularJS front-end plus Redis, ElasticSearch and Heroku

Green Earth Energy and Environmental Solutions Engineer

Sedona, AZ

2012 to 2014

Senior Financial Analyst 2009 to 2012 Santiago, Chile

> skills

Ruby

Javascript

C#

HTML

CSS

MongoDB

SQL

Ruby on Rails

AngularJS

NodeJS

.Net

Redis

Elasticsearch

Heroku

Photoshop

PremierePro

education

Dev Bootcamp Web Development 2014

University of Oregon Sustainability Leadership Certificate Program 2013

Universidad Finis Terrae B.S. Commercial Engineering 2008